<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BracketLab</string>
    <string name="bracketlab_help"><![CDATA[BRACKETLAB HELP

Suggested use

Choose the Camera ID first, then confirm WB, OIS, ISO, focus, exposure list, and temperature before starting a long sequence.

For tripod stacking, keep OIS OFF when possible. OIS can create tiny frame shifts even on a stable tripod.

For clean stacks, prefer stable exposure and stable focus. Use AE and AF as measuring tools, then capture with locked values.

---

Top temperature

The top bar shows:

skin: device surface/body temperature.
camera-usr: camera thermal sensor exposed by the device.

If the phone does not expose skin directly, the app uses modem-skin-usr as a fallback for the skin field.

If a sensor cannot be read, the app shows --°C.

During long stacks, rising temperature can increase noise, color drift, and hot pixels. If the values climb too much, wait for the phone to cool before another sequence.

---

Exposures

Field used to enter or display the exposure list used in the sequence.

Values can be typed manually, generated by AE, calculated by Compute, or expanded using shorthand like:

1/30+3, 1/50+2

This becomes:

1/30
1/30
1/30
1/50
1/50

Clear empties the Exposures field and the log.

---

WB

Defines the white balance correction applied to all frames in the sequence.

Auto WB leaves the device in automatic mode. Manual values lock the chosen WB and help keep a sequence consistent.

---

Folder

Allows the app to create and select the folder where captured sequences will be saved.

---

Camera ID

Selects the camera module used by the app.

Use this first, before AE, AF, Preview, or Capture.

---

OIS

Enables or disables optical image stabilization.

For tripod captures and stacking, OIS OFF is recommended to avoid small stabilization motor corrections between frames.

---

Range

Defines the exposure limits used to calculate an HDR bracket.

Short

Shortest exposure time. Used to preserve highlights and avoid clipping.

Long

Longest exposure time. Used to recover shadow detail.

Get

Shows a temporary preview of the selected exposure, useful for checking clipping, dark areas, or loss of detail.

---

Bracket Parameters

EV defines the spacing between frames.

0.5 EV creates more frames and smoother transitions.

1.0 EV creates fewer frames and lighter files.

Compute calculates the frame list between Short and Long and overwrites Exposures.

---

Live Focus

Opens a preview with a focus slider and digital crop to help fine focus adjustment.

When the slider is released, the selected value is inserted into the Focus field.

---

Focus Bracketing

Focus Start defines the nearest focus point.

Focus End defines the farthest focus point.

Frames defines how many focus steps will be generated.

Get Values distributes focus values evenly between Focus Start and Focus End.

If the Frames field is used only for stacking, without Focus Start and Focus End, use AF normally and avoid generating focus values.

---

AE

Performs automatic exposure metering.

It inserts the measured exposure list and ISO into the fields.

The - and + controls apply AE bias in 0.5 EV steps before metering.

For stacking, a slightly brighter exposure can improve signal, as long as highlights are not clipped.

---

AF

Runs autofocus once, reads the final focus state, then holds focus so the lens does not refocus between frames.

This is useful when continuous autofocus would move during capture.

---

Capture Parameters

ISO defines sensor gain.

Focus shows or defines the current focus value.

Interval defines the time between frames.

Delay defines the wait time before the sequence starts.

---

Preview

Opens a 1440 x 1080 preview using a 3:4 display area from the 4:3 sensor.

Use the exposure slider to brighten or darken the preview.

Use the zoom slider to inspect focus and detail.

Touching the preview closes it. Capture can also be started directly after preview use.

---

Capture

Starts the capture sequence using the configured parameters.
]]></string>
</resources>
